<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<strings>
  <schematron.title>Mobility (v1.1.0)</schematron.title>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.1>Checksum must specify exactly one algorithm (currently only SHA-1 is supported) (spdx:algorithm)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.1>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.10>ERROR: Missing or invalid mobility data standard. You must specify exactly one standard from https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/mobility-data-standard/ or provide a mobilitydcatap:MobilityDataStandard instance. (mobilitydcatap:MobilityDataStandard)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.10>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.11>ERROR: Invalid application layer protocol. If provided, this must be from https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/application-layer-protocol and you cannot specify more than one. (mobilitydcatap:applicationLayerProtocol)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.11>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.12>ERROR: Invalid character encoding. If provided, this must be a literal value (e.g., 'UTF-8') and you cannot specify more than one. (content:characterEncoding)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.12>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.13>ERROR: Invalid communication method. If provided, this must be from https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/communication-method (e.g., push or pull) and you cannot specify more than one. (mobilitydcatap:communicationMethod)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.13>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.14>ERROR: Invalid data format notes. If provided, this must be a literal text value and you cannot specify more than one. (mobilitydcatap:dataFormatNotes)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.14>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.15>ERROR: Invalid grammar. If provided, this must be from https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/grammar and you cannot specify more than one. (mobilitydcatap:grammar)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.15>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.16>ERROR: Invalid sample. If provided, this must be a rdfs:Resource pointing to a sample distribution of the dataset. (adms:sample)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.16>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.17>ERROR: Invalid temporal coverage. If provided, this must be a dct:PeriodOfTime instance specifying the beginning and end times, and you cannot specify more than one. (dct:temporal)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.17>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.18>Catalogue must link to at least one dataset (dcat:dataset)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.18>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.19>Catalogue must have at least one description (dct:description)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.19>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.2>Checksum must specify exactly one checksum value as a hexadecimal string (spdx:checksumValue)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.2>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.20>Catalogue must have exactly one homepage (foaf:homepage)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.20>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.21>Catalogue must have exactly one publisher (dct:publisher)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.21>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.22>Catalogue must link to at least one catalog record (dcat:record)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.22>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.23>Catalogue must have at least one spatial property (dct:spatial)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.23>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.24>Catalogue must have at least one title (dct:title)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.24>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.25>Language must be either a dct:LinguisticSystem or a valid EU Publications Office language authority URI (dct:language)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.25>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.26>License must be a dct:LicenseDocument and can appear at most once (dct:license)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.26>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.27>Theme taxonomy must be a skos:ConceptScheme (dcat:themeTaxonomy)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.27>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.28>Has part must be a dcat:Catalog (dct:hasPart)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.28>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.29>Identifier must be a literal and can appear at most once (dct:identifier)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.29>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.3>ERROR: Invalid standard name. If provided, this must be a URI from the controlled vocabulary at https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/mobility-data-standard/ and you cannot specify more than one. (dct:conformsTo)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.3>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.30>Is part of must be a dcat:Catalog and can appear at most once (dct:isPartOf)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.30>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.31>Other identifier must be an adms:Identifier and can appear at most once (adms:identifier)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.31>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.32>ERROR: Invalid quality annotation resource. If provided, this must be a literal value (either a URL linking to quality details or textual information using the Web Annotation Data Model format) and you cannot specify more than one. (oa:hasBody)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.32>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.33>ERROR: Invalid quality annotation target. If provided, this must reference a dcat:Dataset (the dataset being described by this quality annotation) and you cannot specify more than one. (oa:hasTarget)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.33>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.34>Administrative area must be a literal and can appear at most once (locn:adminUnitL2)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.34>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.35>City must be a literal and can appear at most once (locn:postName)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.35>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.36>Country must be a literal and can appear at most once (locn:adminUnitL1)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.36>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.37>Postal code must be a literal and can appear at most once (locn:postCode)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.37>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.38>Street address must be a literal and can appear at most once (locn:thoroughfare)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.38>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.39>ERROR: Invalid gazetteer. If provided, this must be a valid IRI identifying a geographic naming system, and you cannot specify more than one. (skos:inScheme)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.39>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.4>[{'@value': 'This property describes the version of the mobility data standard, as applied within the delivered content. A version might be, e.g., DATEX II v3.2. This information is provided in a textual format. To avoid ambiguity, only short version identifiers SHOULD be used, e.g., only 3.2, without redundant acronyms such as v, underscores etc.'}, {'@value': 'This property MAY be used to describe the target of the quality annotation, referring back to the dataset being described. I.e., it is the inverse property of "dqv:hasQualityAnnotation" for class Dataset.'}] (owl:versionInfo)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.4>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.40>ERROR: Invalid geographic identifier. This must be a URI from one of the following authorities: EU continent list, EU country list, EU place list, Geonames, or NUTS codes (e.g., http://publications.europa.eu/resource/authority/country/FRA). (dct:identifier)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.40>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.41>ERROR: Invalid geographic name. If provided, this must be a literal text value representing the preferred name of the location. Multiple values can be provided for different languages. (skos:prefLabel)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.41>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.42>ERROR: Missing or invalid accrual periodicity. This is mandatory in mobilityDCAT-AP and must specify how frequently the dataset is updated using a value from http://publications.europa.eu/resource/authority/frequency/ (dct:accrualPeriodicity)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.42>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.43>ERROR: Missing mobility theme. You must select at least one theme from the controlled vocabulary at https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/mobility-theme. (mobilitydcatap:mobilityTheme)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.43>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.44>ERROR: Invalid georeferencing method. You must select a valid method from https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/georeferencing-method. (mobilitydcatap:georeferencingMethod)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.44>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.45>ERROR: Invalid network coverage. You must specify which part of the transport network is covered using values from https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/network-coverage. (mobilitydcatap:networkCoverage)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.45>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.46>ERROR: Invalid spatial reference system. You must use an EPSG code from the OGC register in the format http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/XXXX. (dct:conformsTo)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.46>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.47>ERROR: Invalid rights holder. You must specify an entity (foaf:Agent) that legally owns or holds the rights to this dataset. (dct:rightsHolder)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.47>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.48>ERROR: Invalid transport mode. You must select at least one mode from https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/transport-mode (e.g., road, rail, air, water). (mobilitydcatap:transportMode)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.48>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.49>ERROR: Invalid legislation reference. If provided, this must be a skos:Concept referencing relevant legal frameworks, preferably using European Legislation Identifiers [ELI]. (dcat-ap:applicableLegislation)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.49>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.5>ERROR: Invalid schema. If provided, this must be a rdfs:Resource referencing the schema of the mobility data standard used in the content (either a portal-internal catalogue, individual schema, or external catalogue). (mobilitydcatap:schema)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.5>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.50>ERROR: Invalid assessment result. If provided, this must be a mobilitydcatap:Assessment instance with details about the assessment process and outcomes. (mobilitydcatap:assessmentResult)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.50>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.51>ERROR: Invalid information service. If provided, you must select from the predefined services at https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/intended-information-service. (mobilitydcatap:intentedInformationService)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.51>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.52>ERROR: Invalid quality annotation. If provided, this must be a dqv:QualityAnnotation instance with methods, metrics, and results of quality assessment. (dqv:hasQualityAnnotation)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.52>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.53>ERROR: Missing or invalid email address. You must provide at least one email in the format 'mailto:example@example.com'. (vcard:hasEmail)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.53>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.54>ERROR: Missing name. You must provide at least one name as a literal text value. (vcard:fn)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.54>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.55>ERROR: Invalid URL. If provided, this must be a valid URL in URI format and you cannot specify more than one. (vcard:hasURL)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.55>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.56>ERROR: Invalid address. If provided, this must be a vcard:Address instance and you cannot specify more than one. (vcard:hasAddress)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.56>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.57>ERROR: Invalid affiliation. If provided, this must be a literal text value and you cannot specify more than one. (vcard:organization-name)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.57>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.58>ERROR: Invalid phone number. If provided, this must be in the format 'tel:+1234567890' and you cannot specify more than one. (vcard:hasTelephone)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.58>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.59>ERROR: Missing agent name. You must provide at least one name as a literal text value. Multiple names can be provided for different languages. (foaf:name)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.59>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.6>Catalogue Record must have at least one language (either dct:LinguisticSystem or EU authority URI) (dct:language)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.6>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.60>ERROR: Invalid agent type. If provided, this must be a skos:Concept from the controlled vocabulary and you cannot specify more than one. (dct:type)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.60>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.61>ERROR: Invalid address. If provided, this must be a locn:Address instance specified as either a blank node or IRI. (locn:address)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.61>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.62>ERROR: Invalid affiliation. If provided, this must be an org:Organization instance. (org:memberOf)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.62>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.63>ERROR: Invalid email address. If provided, this must be an IRI using the mailto: scheme (e.g., mailto:example@example.com). (foaf:mbox)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.63>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.64>ERROR: Invalid first name. If provided, this must be a literal text value and you cannot specify more than one. (foaf:firstName)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.64>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.65>ERROR: Invalid phone number. If provided, this must be an IRI using the tel: scheme (e.g., tel:+1234567890). (foaf:phone)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.65>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.66>ERROR: Invalid surname. If provided, this must be a literal text value and you cannot specify more than one. (foaf:surname)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.66>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.67>ERROR: Invalid workplace homepage. If provided, this must be a rdfs:Resource (a URL) and you cannot specify more than one. (foaf:workplaceHomepage)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.67>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.68>ERROR: Missing or invalid conditions for access and usage. You must specify exactly one value from the controlled vocabulary at https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/conditions-for-access-and-usage (e.g., free use, contract required, license required). (dct:type)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.68>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.69>ERROR: Invalid additional information. If provided, this must be a literal text value describing additional access, usage, or licensing details. Multiple values can be provided for different languages. (rdfs:label)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.69>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.7>Catalogue Record must link to exactly one dataset as primary topic (foaf:primaryTopic)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.7>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.70>Category Scheme must have at least one title (dct:title)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.70>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.71>Category must have at least one preferred label (skos:prefLabel)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.71>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.72>Category scheme must be a skos:ConceptScheme and can appear at most once (skos:inScheme)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.72>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.73>ERROR: Invalid assessment result. If provided, this must be a rdfs:Resource (either a URL linking to details or using the Web Annotation Data Model format), and you cannot specify more than one. (oa:hasBody)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.73>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.74>ERROR: Invalid standard license identifier. If provided, this must reference a license from http://publications.europa.eu/resource/authority/access-right and you cannot specify more than one. (dct:identifier)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.74>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.75>ERROR: Invalid license text. If provided, this must be a literal text value containing the full license text and you cannot specify more than one per language. (rdfs:label)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.75>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.8>Publisher must be a foaf:Agent and can appear at most once (dct:publisher)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.8>
  <mobility-110.pattern.assert.9>Source must be a dcat:CatalogRecord (dct:source)</mobility-110.pattern.assert.9>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.1>Checksum must specify exactly one algorithm (currently only SHA-1 is supported) (spdx:algorithm)</mobility-110.pattern.report.1>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.10>ERROR: Missing or invalid mobility data standard. You must specify exactly one standard from https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/mobility-data-standard/ or provide a mobilitydcatap:MobilityDataStandard instance. (mobilitydcatap:MobilityDataStandard)</mobility-110.pattern.report.10>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.11>ERROR: Invalid application layer protocol. If provided, this must be from https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/application-layer-protocol and you cannot specify more than one. (mobilitydcatap:applicationLayerProtocol)</mobility-110.pattern.report.11>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.12>ERROR: Invalid character encoding. If provided, this must be a literal value (e.g., 'UTF-8') and you cannot specify more than one. (content:characterEncoding)</mobility-110.pattern.report.12>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.13>ERROR: Invalid communication method. If provided, this must be from https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/communication-method (e.g., push or pull) and you cannot specify more than one. (mobilitydcatap:communicationMethod)</mobility-110.pattern.report.13>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.14>ERROR: Invalid data format notes. If provided, this must be a literal text value and you cannot specify more than one. (mobilitydcatap:dataFormatNotes)</mobility-110.pattern.report.14>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.15>ERROR: Invalid grammar. If provided, this must be from https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/grammar and you cannot specify more than one. (mobilitydcatap:grammar)</mobility-110.pattern.report.15>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.16>ERROR: Invalid sample. If provided, this must be a rdfs:Resource pointing to a sample distribution of the dataset. (adms:sample)</mobility-110.pattern.report.16>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.17>ERROR: Invalid temporal coverage. If provided, this must be a dct:PeriodOfTime instance specifying the beginning and end times, and you cannot specify more than one. (dct:temporal)</mobility-110.pattern.report.17>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.18>Catalogue must link to at least one dataset (dcat:dataset)</mobility-110.pattern.report.18>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.19>Catalogue must have at least one description (dct:description)</mobility-110.pattern.report.19>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.2>Checksum must specify exactly one checksum value as a hexadecimal string (spdx:checksumValue)</mobility-110.pattern.report.2>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.20>Catalogue must have exactly one homepage (foaf:homepage)</mobility-110.pattern.report.20>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.21>Catalogue must have exactly one publisher (dct:publisher)</mobility-110.pattern.report.21>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.22>Catalogue must link to at least one catalog record (dcat:record)</mobility-110.pattern.report.22>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.23>Catalogue must have at least one spatial property (dct:spatial)</mobility-110.pattern.report.23>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.24>Catalogue must have at least one title (dct:title)</mobility-110.pattern.report.24>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.25>Language must be either a dct:LinguisticSystem or a valid EU Publications Office language authority URI (dct:language)</mobility-110.pattern.report.25>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.26>License must be a dct:LicenseDocument and can appear at most once (dct:license)</mobility-110.pattern.report.26>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.27>Theme taxonomy must be a skos:ConceptScheme (dcat:themeTaxonomy)</mobility-110.pattern.report.27>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.28>Has part must be a dcat:Catalog (dct:hasPart)</mobility-110.pattern.report.28>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.29>Identifier must be a literal and can appear at most once (dct:identifier)</mobility-110.pattern.report.29>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.3>ERROR: Invalid standard name. If provided, this must be a URI from the controlled vocabulary at https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/mobility-data-standard/ and you cannot specify more than one. (dct:conformsTo)</mobility-110.pattern.report.3>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.30>Is part of must be a dcat:Catalog and can appear at most once (dct:isPartOf)</mobility-110.pattern.report.30>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.31>Other identifier must be an adms:Identifier and can appear at most once (adms:identifier)</mobility-110.pattern.report.31>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.32>ERROR: Invalid quality annotation resource. If provided, this must be a literal value (either a URL linking to quality details or textual information using the Web Annotation Data Model format) and you cannot specify more than one. (oa:hasBody)</mobility-110.pattern.report.32>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.33>ERROR: Invalid quality annotation target. If provided, this must reference a dcat:Dataset (the dataset being described by this quality annotation) and you cannot specify more than one. (oa:hasTarget)</mobility-110.pattern.report.33>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.34>Administrative area must be a literal and can appear at most once (locn:adminUnitL2)</mobility-110.pattern.report.34>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.35>City must be a literal and can appear at most once (locn:postName)</mobility-110.pattern.report.35>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.36>Country must be a literal and can appear at most once (locn:adminUnitL1)</mobility-110.pattern.report.36>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.37>Postal code must be a literal and can appear at most once (locn:postCode)</mobility-110.pattern.report.37>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.38>Street address must be a literal and can appear at most once (locn:thoroughfare)</mobility-110.pattern.report.38>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.39>ERROR: Invalid gazetteer. If provided, this must be a valid IRI identifying a geographic naming system, and you cannot specify more than one. (skos:inScheme)</mobility-110.pattern.report.39>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.4>[{'@value': 'This property describes the version of the mobility data standard, as applied within the delivered content. A version might be, e.g., DATEX II v3.2. This information is provided in a textual format. To avoid ambiguity, only short version identifiers SHOULD be used, e.g., only 3.2, without redundant acronyms such as v, underscores etc.'}, {'@value': 'This property MAY be used to describe the target of the quality annotation, referring back to the dataset being described. I.e., it is the inverse property of "dqv:hasQualityAnnotation" for class Dataset.'}] (owl:versionInfo)</mobility-110.pattern.report.4>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.40>ERROR: Invalid geographic identifier. This must be a URI from one of the following authorities: EU continent list, EU country list, EU place list, Geonames, or NUTS codes (e.g., http://publications.europa.eu/resource/authority/country/FRA). (dct:identifier)</mobility-110.pattern.report.40>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.41>ERROR: Invalid geographic name. If provided, this must be a literal text value representing the preferred name of the location. Multiple values can be provided for different languages. (skos:prefLabel)</mobility-110.pattern.report.41>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.42>ERROR: Missing or invalid accrual periodicity. This is mandatory in mobilityDCAT-AP and must specify how frequently the dataset is updated using a value from http://publications.europa.eu/resource/authority/frequency/ (dct:accrualPeriodicity)</mobility-110.pattern.report.42>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.43>ERROR: Missing mobility theme. You must select at least one theme from the controlled vocabulary at https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/mobility-theme. (mobilitydcatap:mobilityTheme)</mobility-110.pattern.report.43>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.44>ERROR: Invalid georeferencing method. You must select a valid method from https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/georeferencing-method. (mobilitydcatap:georeferencingMethod)</mobility-110.pattern.report.44>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.45>ERROR: Invalid network coverage. You must specify which part of the transport network is covered using values from https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/network-coverage. (mobilitydcatap:networkCoverage)</mobility-110.pattern.report.45>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.46>ERROR: Invalid spatial reference system. You must use an EPSG code from the OGC register in the format http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/XXXX. (dct:conformsTo)</mobility-110.pattern.report.46>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.47>ERROR: Invalid rights holder. You must specify an entity (foaf:Agent) that legally owns or holds the rights to this dataset. (dct:rightsHolder)</mobility-110.pattern.report.47>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.48>ERROR: Invalid transport mode. You must select at least one mode from https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/transport-mode (e.g., road, rail, air, water). (mobilitydcatap:transportMode)</mobility-110.pattern.report.48>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.49>ERROR: Invalid legislation reference. If provided, this must be a skos:Concept referencing relevant legal frameworks, preferably using European Legislation Identifiers [ELI]. (dcat-ap:applicableLegislation)</mobility-110.pattern.report.49>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.5>ERROR: Invalid schema. If provided, this must be a rdfs:Resource referencing the schema of the mobility data standard used in the content (either a portal-internal catalogue, individual schema, or external catalogue). (mobilitydcatap:schema)</mobility-110.pattern.report.5>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.50>ERROR: Invalid assessment result. If provided, this must be a mobilitydcatap:Assessment instance with details about the assessment process and outcomes. (mobilitydcatap:assessmentResult)</mobility-110.pattern.report.50>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.51>ERROR: Invalid information service. If provided, you must select from the predefined services at https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/intended-information-service. (mobilitydcatap:intentedInformationService)</mobility-110.pattern.report.51>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.52>ERROR: Invalid quality annotation. If provided, this must be a dqv:QualityAnnotation instance with methods, metrics, and results of quality assessment. (dqv:hasQualityAnnotation)</mobility-110.pattern.report.52>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.53>ERROR: Missing or invalid email address. You must provide at least one email in the format 'mailto:example@example.com'. (vcard:hasEmail)</mobility-110.pattern.report.53>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.54>ERROR: Missing name. You must provide at least one name as a literal text value. (vcard:fn)</mobility-110.pattern.report.54>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.55>ERROR: Invalid URL. If provided, this must be a valid URL in URI format and you cannot specify more than one. (vcard:hasURL)</mobility-110.pattern.report.55>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.56>ERROR: Invalid address. If provided, this must be a vcard:Address instance and you cannot specify more than one. (vcard:hasAddress)</mobility-110.pattern.report.56>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.57>ERROR: Invalid affiliation. If provided, this must be a literal text value and you cannot specify more than one. (vcard:organization-name)</mobility-110.pattern.report.57>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.58>ERROR: Invalid phone number. If provided, this must be in the format 'tel:+1234567890' and you cannot specify more than one. (vcard:hasTelephone)</mobility-110.pattern.report.58>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.59>ERROR: Missing agent name. You must provide at least one name as a literal text value. Multiple names can be provided for different languages. (foaf:name)</mobility-110.pattern.report.59>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.6>Catalogue Record must have at least one language (either dct:LinguisticSystem or EU authority URI) (dct:language)</mobility-110.pattern.report.6>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.60>ERROR: Invalid agent type. If provided, this must be a skos:Concept from the controlled vocabulary and you cannot specify more than one. (dct:type)</mobility-110.pattern.report.60>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.61>ERROR: Invalid address. If provided, this must be a locn:Address instance specified as either a blank node or IRI. (locn:address)</mobility-110.pattern.report.61>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.62>ERROR: Invalid affiliation. If provided, this must be an org:Organization instance. (org:memberOf)</mobility-110.pattern.report.62>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.63>ERROR: Invalid email address. If provided, this must be an IRI using the mailto: scheme (e.g., mailto:example@example.com). (foaf:mbox)</mobility-110.pattern.report.63>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.64>ERROR: Invalid first name. If provided, this must be a literal text value and you cannot specify more than one. (foaf:firstName)</mobility-110.pattern.report.64>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.65>ERROR: Invalid phone number. If provided, this must be an IRI using the tel: scheme (e.g., tel:+1234567890). (foaf:phone)</mobility-110.pattern.report.65>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.66>ERROR: Invalid surname. If provided, this must be a literal text value and you cannot specify more than one. (foaf:surname)</mobility-110.pattern.report.66>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.67>ERROR: Invalid workplace homepage. If provided, this must be a rdfs:Resource (a URL) and you cannot specify more than one. (foaf:workplaceHomepage)</mobility-110.pattern.report.67>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.68>ERROR: Missing or invalid conditions for access and usage. You must specify exactly one value from the controlled vocabulary at https://w3id.org/mobilitydcat-ap/conditions-for-access-and-usage (e.g., free use, contract required, license required). (dct:type)</mobility-110.pattern.report.68>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.69>ERROR: Invalid additional information. If provided, this must be a literal text value describing additional access, usage, or licensing details. Multiple values can be provided for different languages. (rdfs:label)</mobility-110.pattern.report.69>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.7>Catalogue Record must link to exactly one dataset as primary topic (foaf:primaryTopic)</mobility-110.pattern.report.7>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.70>Category Scheme must have at least one title (dct:title)</mobility-110.pattern.report.70>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.71>Category must have at least one preferred label (skos:prefLabel)</mobility-110.pattern.report.71>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.72>Category scheme must be a skos:ConceptScheme and can appear at most once (skos:inScheme)</mobility-110.pattern.report.72>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.73>ERROR: Invalid assessment result. If provided, this must be a rdfs:Resource (either a URL linking to details or using the Web Annotation Data Model format), and you cannot specify more than one. (oa:hasBody)</mobility-110.pattern.report.73>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.74>ERROR: Invalid standard license identifier. If provided, this must reference a license from http://publications.europa.eu/resource/authority/access-right and you cannot specify more than one. (dct:identifier)</mobility-110.pattern.report.74>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.75>ERROR: Invalid license text. If provided, this must be a literal text value containing the full license text and you cannot specify more than one per language. (rdfs:label)</mobility-110.pattern.report.75>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.8>Publisher must be a foaf:Agent and can appear at most once (dct:publisher)</mobility-110.pattern.report.8>
  <mobility-110.pattern.report.9>Source must be a dcat:CatalogRecord (dct:source)</mobility-110.pattern.report.9>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.1>Algorithm - This property identifies the algorithm used to produce the subject Checksum. Currently, SHA-1 is the only supported algorithm.</mobility-110.pattern.title.1>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.10>Mobility data standard - This property describes the mobility data standard, as applied for the delivered content within the Distribution. A mobility data standard, e.g., DATEX II, combines syntax and semantic definitions of entities in a certain domain (e.g., for DATEX II: road traffic information), and optionally adds technical rules for data exchange.</mobility-110.pattern.title.10>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.11>Application layer protocol - This property describes the transmitting channel, i.e., the Application Layer Protocol, of the distribution.</mobility-110.pattern.title.11>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.12>Character encoding - This property describes the technical encoding format of the delivered content within the Distribution. It is described via a character set standard.</mobility-110.pattern.title.12>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.13>Communication method - This property indicates for data services, e.g., data feeds, if the data interface of the data provider system functions in a push or pull mode.</mobility-110.pattern.title.13>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.14>Data format notes - This property contains any additional information about the format of the delivered content within the Distribution (see the corresponding properties dct:format, mobilitydcatap:mobilityDataStandard, mobilitydcatap:grammar), in a textual format. This might be about, e.g., extensions being used in a mobilitydcatap:mobilityDataStandard.</mobility-110.pattern.title.14>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.15>Grammar - This property describes the technical data grammar format of the delivered content within the Distribution. It describes the standard on top of the elementary syntax that describe data structures in the dataset. This is a sub-property of dct:conformsTo.</mobility-110.pattern.title.15>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.16>Sample - This property refers to a sample Distribution of the Dataset. A data sample allows data users to investigate the data content and data structure, without subscribing to a data feed or downloading a complete data set. In [DCAT-AP-v2.0.1], there is a property adms:sample under the class dcat:Dataset , with a range of dcat:Distribution. This implies, that all mandatory properties from dcat:Distribution, e.g., mobilitydcatap:mobilityDataStandard, must be applied. To simplify the description of the Sample, mobilityDCAT-AP recommends to describe the Sample via a property under class dcat:Distribution. It is assumed that all other properties, as already populated for dcat:Distribution, e.g., mobilitydcatap:mobilityDataStandard, also apply for the description of the data sample.</mobility-110.pattern.title.16>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.17>Temporal coverage - This property describes the beginning and end of the time interval when a data service, e.g., a data feed, is delivered technically via the data platform. If there is no entry it means that the publication gets valid immediately and the timestamp is the same as the metadata timestamp.</mobility-110.pattern.title.17>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.18>Dataset - This property links the mobility data portal with a dataset that is described at the mobility data portal.</mobility-110.pattern.title.18>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.19>Description - This property contains a free-text, individual name of the mobility data platform itself.</mobility-110.pattern.title.19>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.2>Checksum value - This property provides a lower case hexadecimal encoded digest value produced using a specific algorithm.</mobility-110.pattern.title.2>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.20>Homepage - This property refers to a Web page that acts as the main page for the mobility data portal.</mobility-110.pattern.title.20>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.21>Publisher - This property refers to an organisation, if applicable a person, which is responsible for creation and maintenance of the mobility data platform.</mobility-110.pattern.title.21>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.22>Record - This property refers to a metadata record that is part of the mobility data portal.</mobility-110.pattern.title.22>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.23>Spatial / geographic - This property refers to a country code where the data platform is hosted.</mobility-110.pattern.title.23>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.24>Title - This property contains a name given to the mobility data portal.</mobility-110.pattern.title.24>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.25>Language - This property refers to a language used in the user interface of the mobility data portal.</mobility-110.pattern.title.25>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.26>Licence - This property refers to the licence under which the Catalogue can be used or reused.</mobility-110.pattern.title.26>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.27>Themes - This property refers to a knowledge organization system used to classify the mobility data portal's Datasets.</mobility-110.pattern.title.27>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.28>Has part - This property refers to a related Catalogue that is part of the described mobility data portal.</mobility-110.pattern.title.28>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.29>Identifier - This property MAY contain an identifier for the mobility data portal. Allows a unique identification of the individual portal and is used for referencing, e.g., when exchanging metadata between mobility data portals.</mobility-110.pattern.title.29>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.3>Standard name - This property describes the name of the mobility data standard. This property is necessary for the following CASE 1: A custom instance of mobilitydcatap:MobilityDataStandard is defined. Such custom instance is recommended when the mobility data standard is detailed out via properties owl:versionInfo and/or mobilitydcatap:schema. The property dct:conformsTo would then name the mobility data standard via a controlled vocabulary. In the alternative CASE 2, the name the mobility data standard is directly named as range of mobilitydcatap:MobilityDataStandard, again via the same controlled vocabulary.</mobility-110.pattern.title.3>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.30>Is part of - This property refers to a related Catalogue in which the described mobility data portal is physically or logically included.</mobility-110.pattern.title.30>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.31>Other identifier - This property MAY be used as an additional identifier, besides dct:identifier. It MAY be referring to a dedicated, EU-wide identificator system of NAPS or other portals, to be introduced in the future.</mobility-110.pattern.title.31>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.32>Quality annotation resource - This property MAY be used to describe any quality aspects regarding the delivered content, in form of a URL linking to further details or results. Alternatively, textual information MAY be provided using the Embedded Textual Body construction of the Web Annotation Data Model [Web-Annotation-Data-Model], which allows to specify text formats and languages which might be relevant for multilingual purposes.</mobility-110.pattern.title.32>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.33>Quality annotation target - This property MAY be used to describe the target of the quality annotation, referring back to the dataset being described. I.e., it is the inverse property of dqv:hasQualityAnnotation  for class Dataset.</mobility-110.pattern.title.33>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.34>Administrative area - The administrative area of an Address of the Agent. Depending on the country, this corresponds to a province, a county, a region, or a state.</mobility-110.pattern.title.34>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.35>City - The city of an Address of the Agent.</mobility-110.pattern.title.35>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.36>Country - The country of an Address of the Agent.</mobility-110.pattern.title.36>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.37>Postal code - The postal code of an Address of the Agent.</mobility-110.pattern.title.37>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.38>Street address - In mobilityDCAT-AP, this is a recommended property to be used for Address (Agent)</mobility-110.pattern.title.38>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.39>Gazetteer - This property MAY be used to specify the gazetteer to which the Location belongs. The value should be an IRI identifying the gazetteer (e.g., http://sws.geonames.org/, http://data.europa.eu/nuts).</mobility-110.pattern.title.39>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.4>Version - [{'@value': 'This property describes the version of the mobility data standard, as applied within the delivered content. A version might be, e.g., DATEX II v3.2. This information is provided in a textual format. To avoid ambiguity, only short version identifiers SHOULD be used, e.g., only 3.2, without redundant acronyms such as v, underscores etc.'}, {'@value': 'This property MAY be used to describe the target of the quality annotation, referring back to the dataset being described. I.e., it is the inverse property of "dqv:hasQualityAnnotation" for class Dataset.'}]</mobility-110.pattern.title.4>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.40>Geographic identifier - This property contains the geographic identifier for the Location, e.g., the URI or other unique identifier in the context of the relevant gazetteer. Identifiers SHOULD be coded via controlled vocabularies such as the EU authority tables, NUTS (Nomenclature des unités territoriales statistiques) or Geonames. This property is analogue to an addition by GEODCAT-AP-v2.0.0.</mobility-110.pattern.title.40>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.41>Geographic name - This property contains a preferred label of the Location. This property can be repeated for parallel language versions of the label - see § 8. Accessibility and Multilingual Aspects.</mobility-110.pattern.title.41>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.42>Accrual periodicity - This property refers to the frequency at which the dataset is updated. The obligation of this property is raised to 'mandatory' in mobilityDCAT-AP.</mobility-110.pattern.title.42>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.43>Mobility theme - This property refers to the mobility-related theme (i.e., a specific subject, category, or type) of the delivered content. A dataset may be associated with multiple themes. A theme is important for data seekers who are interested in a particular type of data content. The theme is described via a controlled vocabulary in two hierarchy levels: The 1st level is a mandatory field labelled Data content category, describing the classification of the data content on an aggregated level. The 2nd level is an optional field labelled Data content sub category, detailing the Data content category via one or several sub-categories. When entering the metadata for one dataset, the data provider would first select one or several options of a Data content category, and then optionally details this with one or more options of corresponding Data content sub category. The platform must be able to handle the dependencies between these two levels, i.e., match the allowed options between the 1st and 2nd level.</mobility-110.pattern.title.43>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.44>Georeferencing method - This property SHOULD be used to specify the georeferencing method used in the dataset.</mobility-110.pattern.title.44>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.45>Network coverage - This property describes the part of the transport network that is covered by the delivered content. For road traffic, the property SHOULD refer to the network classification for which the data is provided. As a minimum, an international or higher-level classification, e.g., via functional road classes, is recommended to allow data search across different countries. In addition, national classifications are allowed.</mobility-110.pattern.title.45>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.46>Reference system - This property SHOULD be used to specify the spatial reference system used in the dataset. Spatial reference systems SHOULD be specified by using the corresponding URIs from the EPSG coordinate reference systems register operated by OGC.</mobility-110.pattern.title.46>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.47>Rights holder - This property refers to an entity that legally owns or holds the rights of the data provided in a dataset. This entity is legally responsible for the content of the data. It is also responsible for any statements about the data quality (if applicable, see property dqv:hasQualityAnnotation) and/or the relevance to legal frameworks (if applicable, see property dcatap:applicableLegislation). This entity is the direct contact for the platform operator or data consumers, who have questions or issues about the contents of a dataset. The Rights Holder will be in many cases identical with the Publisher information for class Dataset (see property dct:publisher) and/or for class Catalogue Record (see property dct:publisher). In this case, the contact data MAY be copied from the corresponding Publisher entries. There might be also cases with non-identical entities: e.g., when one or several Rights Holders contract a third-party Publisher (e.g., an IT service company), which is producing, hosting and publishing a dataset.</mobility-110.pattern.title.47>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.48>Transport mode - This property describes the transport mode that is covered by the delivered content. Data can be valid for more than one mode, so a multiple choice should be applied.</mobility-110.pattern.title.48>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.49>Applicable legislation - This property MAY refer to one or several legal frameworks being relevant for the dataset, e.g., an EC Delegated Regulation which constitutes the purpose of the corresponding data platform (here called National Access Point/NAP), or some other international or national frameworks, e.g., Open Data regulations. For European legal frameworks, it is recommended to use the European Legislation Identifier [ELI] to refer to legislation whenever possible. This property is derived from the DCAT-AP HVD extension</mobility-110.pattern.title.49>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.5>Schema - This property describes the schema of the mobility data standard, as applied within the delivered content. There are differet optiions how to reference the schema. It might be a reference to a portal-internal catalogue of schemas, a reference to an individual schema (that is provided by the data publisher), or a reference to an external catalogue of schemas (like a stakeholder-based DATEX II profile published on the datex2.eu page). The data platform SHOULD keep an archive of commonly used schemas. The data provider SHOULD be able to select an applicable schema from this archive, or to upload an own, individual schema. In any case, the schema should be available as a resource. This is a sub-property of dct:conformsTo.</mobility-110.pattern.title.5>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.50>Assessment result - This property MAY refer to the results and outcomes from an assessment process by some organisation, e.g., a National Body in the context of EU Delegated Regulations. EU Delegated Regulations require Member States to set up procedures to assess the compliance of the Delegated Regulations, e.g. regarding the provisioning of data via a NAP. These assessment processes are handled by National Bodies [NAPCORE-NB] and installed individually in each Member State. The property MAY point to the most recent assessment procedure, including its date, its result as a free-text and/or a link referring to an assessment report online. The difference to the property dqv:hasQualityAnnotation is that the latter one is provided by the data provider, while the assessment results are provided by an external organisation.</mobility-110.pattern.title.50>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.51>Intended information service - This property MAY describe predefined information services, which the data content is intended to support. Such services MAY be, e.g., information services for multimodal mobility, as specified by EC Delegated Regulation 2017/1926 [EC-MMTIS-DR]. Examples of such services include location search, which is based on a datasets with address identifiers, or trip plan computation, which is based on datasets about a road network.</mobility-110.pattern.title.51>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.52>Quality description - This property MAY describe any quality aspects regarding the delivered content, in particular methods, metrics/indicators and results of a quality assessment in the responsibility of the Rights Holder (see property dct:rightsHolder). This information SHOULD assist data consumers in determining the value of data, before actually accessing and processing it. Thus, the information SHOULD be publicly available. Furthermore, it can be helpful for validation processes by 3rd parties, e.g., a National Body in context of EU Delegated Regulations. Quality aspects SHOULD be noted via a free text and/or via URLs linking to further quality information. If there is absolutely no quality information, at least a note quality information is unknown SHOULD be given. If existing quality frameworks have been applied in the quality assessment, e.g., the Quality Packages from the EU EIP and NAPCORE projects [EU-EIP-QP], these frameworks should be referenced.</mobility-110.pattern.title.52>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.53>Email - This property contains an email address of the Kind, specified using fully qualified mailto: URI scheme [RFC6068].</mobility-110.pattern.title.53>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.54>Name - This property contains a name of the Kind. This property can be repeated for different versions of the name (e.g., the name in different languages) - see § 8. Accessibility and Multilingual Aspects.</mobility-110.pattern.title.54>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.55>Url - This property points to a Web site of the Kind.</mobility-110.pattern.title.55>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.56>Address - This property MAY be used to specify the postal address of the Kind.</mobility-110.pattern.title.56>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.57>Affiliation - This property MAY be used to specify the affiliation of the Kind. This property can be repeated for different versions of the name (e.g. the name in different languages) - see § 8. Accessibility and Multilingual Aspects.</mobility-110.pattern.title.57>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.58>Phone - This property MAY be used to provide the phone number of the Kind, specified using fully qualified tel: URI scheme [RFC3966].</mobility-110.pattern.title.58>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.59>Name - This property contains a name of the Agent. This property can be repeated for different versions of the name (e.g. the name in different languages).</mobility-110.pattern.title.59>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.6>Language - This property refers to a language used in the textual metadata describing titles, descriptions, etc. of the metadata entry.</mobility-110.pattern.title.6>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.60>Type - This property refers to a type of the Agent that makes the Catalogue, Catalogue Record, Data Service, or Dataset available. A controlled vocabulary is provided.</mobility-110.pattern.title.60>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.61>Address - This property MAY be used to specify the postal address of the Agent. This property is analogue to an addition by [GEODCAT-AP-v2.0.0].</mobility-110.pattern.title.61>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.62>Affiliation - If the agent is of type person, this property SHOULD be used to specify the affiliation of the Agent, see § 7. Agent Types, Agent Roles and Contact Information. This property is analogue to an addition by [GEODCAT-AP-v2.0.0].</mobility-110.pattern.title.62>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.63>Email - This property SHOULD be used to provide the email address of the Agent, specified using fully qualified mailto: URI scheme [RFC6068]. The email SHOULD be used to establish a communication channel to the agent.</mobility-110.pattern.title.63>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.64>First name - If the agent is of type person, this property SHOULD be used to specify the first name of the Agent, see section § 7. Agent Types, Agent Roles and Contact Information.</mobility-110.pattern.title.64>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.65>Phone - This property MAY be used to provide the phone number of the Agent, specified using fully qualified tel: URI scheme [RFC3966]. This property is analogue to an addition by [GEODCAT-AP-v2.0.0].</mobility-110.pattern.title.65>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.66>Surname - If the agent is of type person, this property SHOULD be used to specify the surname of the Agent, see section 7.</mobility-110.pattern.title.66>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.67>Work place homepage url - This property MAY be used to specify the Web site of the Agent.</mobility-110.pattern.title.67>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.68>Conditions for access and usage - This property SHOULD be used to indicate the conditions if any contracts, licences and/or are applied for the use of the dataset. The conditions are declared on an aggregated level: whether a free and unrestricted use is possible, a contract has to be concluded and/or a licence has to be agreed on to use a dataset.</mobility-110.pattern.title.68>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.69>Additional information for access and usage - This property MAY describes in a textual form any additional access, usage or licensing information, besides other information under classes dct:RightsStatement and dct:LicenseDocument. This property can be repeated for parallel language versions of the name - see § 8. Accessibility and Multilingual Aspects.</mobility-110.pattern.title.69>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.7>Primary topic - This property links the metadata entry to the dataset described in the entry.</mobility-110.pattern.title.7>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.70>Title - This property contains a name of the Category Scheme. May be repeated for different versions of the name.</mobility-110.pattern.title.70>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.71>Preferred label - This property contains a preferred label of the Category. This property can be repeated for parallel language versions of the label.</mobility-110.pattern.title.71>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.72>Category scheme - This property MAY be used to specify the Category Scheme to which the Category belongs. This property is analogue to an addition by [GEODCAT-AP-v2.0.0].</mobility-110.pattern.title.72>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.73>Assessment result - This property MAY be used to describe the result of the latest assessment procedure, in form of a URL linking to further details or results. Alternatively, textual information MAY be provided using the Embedded Textual Body construction of the Web Annotation Data Model [Web-Annotation-Data-Model], which allows to specify text formats and languages which might be relevant for multilingual purposes.</mobility-110.pattern.title.73>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.74>Standard licence - This property MAY be be used to link to a concrete standard license.</mobility-110.pattern.title.74>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.75>Licence text - This property MAY be used to contain the full text of a Licence Document, as a free text. This MAY be used when there is no standard license that can be linked via property dct:identifier. This property can be repeated for parallel language versions of the name - see § 8. Accessibility and Multilingual Aspects.</mobility-110.pattern.title.75>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.8>Publisher - This property refers to an entity (an organisation or a person), which is responsible for creation and maintenance of the metadata entry on the data platform.</mobility-110.pattern.title.8>
  <mobility-110.pattern.title.9>Source metadata - This property is used for metadata records that are harvested from other portals.</mobility-110.pattern.title.9>
</strings>